In this video, we will go through an example of how to
在这个视频中 我们将通过一个例子
import and export data to and from Spark data frames.
来介绍如何从 Spark 导入和导出数据表
So let's just get started.
让我们开始吧
First, let's take a look at our Spark session.
先看一下 SparkSession
As we discussed in the previous videos,
就像之前的视频中讨论的那样
we can set its parameters.
我们可以给它设置参数
For example, we can add the name of our application.
例如 我们可以给应用程序添加名称
Let me just first import Spark session.
我们先导入 SparkSession
We'd get or create,
getOrCreate 会更新
if the session already exists, we will update it,
已有的 SparkSession
if it doesn't exist,
如果 SparkSession 不存在
a new one will be created as we discussed in a previous video.
新的 SparkSession 就会被创建
So let's see what happen to the parameters.
我们看看参数有啥变化
As you can see I just made a typo, this should be capital C,
我刚打错字了 这应该是大写字母C
and now we can see all the parameters here.
这里可以看到所有参数
We have successfully updated the name of our application,
我们更新了应用程序的名称
and now it's called our first Spark SQL example.
这个新的名称叫 our first Spark SQL example
You can also take a look at the other parameters here.
这里还可以查看其他参数
Let's just load a JSON file into a Spark data frame.
我们现在把 JSON 文件加载到 Spark dataframe
In the next few videos, we will use a dataset
在接下来的几个视频中 我们会使用
that describes log events coming from a music streaming service.
一个音乐云服务的日志数据集
As users use different pages of the application,
当用户使用应用程序的不同页面时
their page requests are logged.
他们对页面的请求会被记录下来
Let's define the pass of this first example called sparkify_log_small.json.
我们先定义一个名叫 sparkify_log_small.json 的路径
I previously saved this file to HDFS on the cluster we run our Spark application on.
我之前已经将这个文件保存到运行 Spark 集群上的HDFS里了
This is just the IP address of the master node.
这是主节点的IP地址
So let's load the JSON file into a data frame called user_log.
我们先将 JSON 文件加载到名为 user_log 的 dataframe 中
To see what we got here,
要看结果的话
let's print the schema with the printSchema method.
我们可以用 printSchema 方法把提纲（schema）打印出来
We have a couple of fields describing the user,
这里有几个描述用户的字段
for example, we have user ID here,
例如 用户ID
first name and last name,
名字和姓氏
and also have information about the request, for example,
并且还有关于请求的信息 例如
the page the user accessed,
用户访问的页面信息
the HTTP method, or the status of the request.
HTTP方法或请求的状态
Let's try the describe method to see what we can learn from our data.
让我们尝试一下 describe 方法 看看能得到啥信息
As you can see, the describe returned the columns we have in this data frame,
如你所见 describe 返回了这个 dataframe 的列名以及字段类型
and their type just as printSchema did.
和 printSchema 差不多
We can also take a look at a particular record.
我们还可以查看特定行的信息
So let's just see how the first one looks like.
那我们看看第一行长啥样
Apparently, cannot make use.
显然 用户 Kenneth 在听一首叫 showaddywaddy 的歌
Was just listening to a, showaddywaddy.
Was just listening to a, showaddywaddy.
We can also use the take method to grab the first few records.
我们也可以使用 take 方法来获取前几条记录
The first record is still the same,
第一条记录和之前相同
but we can see a couple more example how our dataset looks like.
但我们可以多看几条数据 从而对数据集有更清晰的把握
Now that we have successfully loaded our data into this frame,
现在我们已成功将数据加载到 dataframe 中
let's see how to save it into a different format,
接下来我们看看如何将其保存为不同的格式
for example, into a CSV file.
例如 保存为 CSV 文件
I use the same HDFS folder as the input files,
我把输出文件保存在和输入文件同一个 HDFS 文件夹里
and specify the file name here.
在这里命名输出文件名
Let's call our CSV version of this file, sparkify_ log_file.csv.
我把这个 CSV 文件命名为 sparkify_log_file.csv
We can use the right.save method to save this file.
我们可以使用 write.save 方法来保存这个文件
I specify the format as CSV,
将格式设为 CSV
and also set the header to true,
并将标题设置为 true
just to make sure that we can preserve the column names.
确保我们保留了列名称
All right, let's just load the CSV file
好了 现在我们加载一下
we just saved into another data frame.
刚刚保存的 CSV 文件
We can use the read.csv method, specify the same.
我们可以使用 read.csv 方法
If I pass here, that'll be saved,
设置文件路径为我们之前保存CSV 文件的路径
our CSV file, and also set the header to true.
并将 header 设置为 true
Let's check our schema first,
我们先来看看我们的框架
as the same as it was before.
和以前完全相同
We can also take a look at the first few records.
我们再看一下前几条记录
Again, we see the same records as we saw
同样 与我们之前看到的 dataframe 相同
with the other data frame just as expected.
和预期一致
In this video, we went through an example on how to
在这个视频中 我们通过了一个例子
load and save data frames from and to HDFS.
学习了如何从 HDFS 读取和存储 dataframe
If a file is stored in S3,
如果文件存储在 S3 中
you can use the same methods.
你也可以使用相同的方法
When specifying the file past,
关于文件路径
we just need to make sure that we are pointing to
我们只需要确保
the S3 bucket that stores our target file.
目标文件的路径是正确的